Menu Search Subscribe [Donate](https://buddho.org/donate/) Menu [Contact](https://buddho.org/contact/) [Home](https://buddho.org/)

Search [](https://buddho.org/)Language

"Drop by drop is the water pot filled. Likewise, the wise, gathering it little by little, fills himself with good."

Buddha, Dhp 121

[Authors](https://buddho.org/authors/) and [FAQ](https://buddho.org/frequently-asked-questions/)

Switch Language

Do you prefer to read in Dutch?

Carefully translated

Inspiration in your Inbox?

Subscribe to our blog

First Name 

Email Address 

Warning: This form can only be used if JavaScript is enabled in your browser.

Subscribe

 Leave this field empty if you're not a robot: 

Read our [privacy policy](https://buddho.org/privacy-policy/)

Don't worry, we won't spam you

GDPR/AVG Proof

Our Privacy Policy
==================

Here you will find the privacy policy of buddho.org website. We created this Privacy Policy to declare which information we collect, how we use data and which options the users of our website have, according to the guidelines of the [General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/ALL/?uri=celex%3A32016R0679&%3Btid=%20111629722)

Unfortunately, these subjects sound rather technical due to their nature, but we have put much effort into describing the most important things as simply and clearly as possible.

Rights in Accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation
----------------------------------------------------------------

You are granted the following rights in accordance with the provisions of the [GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/) (General Data Protection Regulation) and the Dutch Algemene Verordening Gegevensbescherming (AVG):

* right to rectification (article 16 GDPR)
* right to erasure (“right to be forgotten“) (article 17 GDPR)
* right to restrict processing (article 18 GDPR)
* righ to notification – notification obligation regarding rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing (article 19 GDPR)
* right to data portability (article 20 GDPR)
* Right to object (article 21 GDPR)
* right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing – including profiling – (article 22 GDPR)

If you think that the processing of your data violates the data protection law, or that your data protection rights have been infringed in any other way, you can lodge a complaint with your respective regulatory authority.

The Contact Form
----------------

Buddho.org may process personal information about you because you provided it when you filled out a contact form on the website.

The following personal data will be processed when using the contact form:

1. Your first and/or last name
2. Your e-mail address

The information you provide in the contact form is stored in the recipient’s inbox and used to respond if necessary. The data will not be shared with third parties, unless you subscribe to our newsletter.

If you indicate that you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will share your information with MailChimp with the sole purpose of sending you the newsletter. Your email address will not be added to our MailChimp email list by default.

The Newsletter
--------------

Buddho.org uses Noptin to manage our newsletter from within the WordPress environment. This means that your data stays on our own server, without the intervention of a third party.

We will use the email address provided to send you a monthly update on new posts and occasionally to send you a additional messages or information relating to the meditation system, Buddhism, the meditation group and/or the foundation.

After subscribing you have the option to unsubscribe using the link at the bottom of the newsletter, or you can unsubscribe by [contacting us](https://buddho.org/contact/) and making your wish known.

Donating
--------

In the case of direct donations by bank transfer, we can see the standard details on our statements, which generally apply to bank transfers. For donations via Credit Card we use Mollie, see also their [privacy statement](https://www.mollie.com/nl/privacy).

For credit card payments the privacy statement of the credit card company applies, when paying with Paypal the [privacy statement](https://www.paypal.com/va/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) of Paypal applies.

Your name and email address will be stored for administrative purposes in our secured database. We can also see your name permanently on our statements.

We might use your email address to send a personal thank you note but will not do so more often then twice a year.

Speed & Security
----------------

Buddho.org takes data protection seriously and takes appropriate measures to prevent misuse, loss, unauthorized access, unwanted disclosure and unauthorized modification.

The website uses a reliable SSL Certificate and other security measures, at server, application and connection level, to ensure that your personal data does not fall into the wrong hands.

We use https to transfer information on the internet in a tap-proof manner (data protection through technology design [Article 25 Section 1 GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN&tid=111629722)). With the use of TLS (Transport Layer Security), which is an encryption protocol for safe data transfer on the internet, we can ensure the protection of confidential information.

You can recognize the use of this safeguarding tool by the little lock-symbol, which is situated in your browser’s top left corner, as well as by the use of the letters https (instead of http) as a part of our web address.

The IP address of visitors, user IDs of logged in users, and usernames of login attempts might be conditionally logged to monitor for malicious activity and protect the website from specific attacks. Examples of conditions under which data is stored include login attempts, logout attempts, requesting suspect URLs, making changes to site content, and password updates. This information is stored for 60 days.

### Cloudflare

We use Cloudflare by the company Cloudflare, Inc. (101 Townsend St., San Francisco, CA 94107, USA) on this website to enhance its speed and security. For this, Cloudflare uses cookies and processes user data. Cloudflare, Inc. is an American company that offers a content delivery network and various security services. These services take place between the user and our hosting provider. In the following, we will try to explain in detail what all this means.

#### What is Cloudflare?

A content delivery network (CDN), as provided by Cloudflare, is nothing more than a network of servers that are connected to each other. Cloudflare has deployed servers around the world, which ensure websites can appear on your screen faster. Simply put, Cloudflare makes copies of our website and places them on its own servers. Thus, when you visit our website, a load distribution system ensures that the main part of our website is delivered by a server that can display our website to you as quickly as possible. The CDN significantly shortens the route of the transmitted data to your browser. Thus, Cloudflare does not only deliver our website’s content from our hosting server, but from servers from all over the world. Cloudflare is particularly helpful for users from abroad, since pages can be delivered from a nearby server. In addition to the fast delivery of websites, Cloudflare also offers various security services, such as DDoS protection, or the web application firewall.

#### Why do we use Cloudflare on our website?

Of course, we want our website to offer you the best possible service. Cloudflare helps us make our website faster and more secure. Cloudflare offers us web optimisations as well as security services such as DDoS protection and a web firewall. Moreover, this includes a Reverse-Proxy and the content distribution network (CDN). Cloudflare blocks threats and limits abusive bots as well as crawlers that waste our bandwidth and server resources. By storing our website in local data center’s and blocking spam software, Cloudflare enables us to reduce our bandwidth usage by about 60%. Furthermore, the provision of content through a data centre near you and certain web optimizations carried out there, cut the average loading time of a website in about half. According to Cloudflare, the setting “I’m Under Attack Mode” can be used to mitigate further attacks by displaying a JavaScript calculation task that must be solved before a user can access a website. Overall, this makes our website significantly more powerful and less susceptible to spam or other attacks.

#### What data is stored by Cloudflare?

Cloudflare generally only transmits data that is controlled by website operators. Therefore, Cloudflare does not determine the content, but the website operator themselves does. Additionally, Cloudflare may collect certain information about the use of our website and may process data we send or data which Cloudflare has received certain instructions for. Mostly, Cloudflare receives data such as IP addresses, contacts and protocol information, security fingerprints and websites’ performance data. Log data for example helps Cloudflare identify new threats. That way, Cloudflare can ensure a high level of security for our website. As part of their services, Cloudflare process this data in compliance with the applicable laws. Of course, this also includes the compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Furthermore, Cloudflare uses a cookie for security reasons. The cookie is used to identify individual users behind a shared IP address, and to apply security settings for each individual user. The cookie is very useful, if you e.g. use our website from a restaurant where several infected computers are located. However, if your computer is trustworthy, we can recognise that with the cookie. Hence, you will be able to freely and carelessly surf our website, despite the infected PCs in your area. Another point that is important to know, is that this cookie does not store any personal data. The cookie is essential for Cloudflare’s security functions and cannot be deactivated.

Statistics
----------

This website collects visitor statistics on a completely anonymous basis via Google Analytics.

Google Analytics uses cookies. We have a processing agreement with Google. The data is processed anonymously and can therefore not be traced back to the individual. The data is not shared with Google for third-party use and Google isn’t allowed to process the data.

Further Cookies
---------------

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we store a temporary cookie to determine whether your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal information and is deleted when you close your browser.

Once you log in, we will store some cookies related to your login information and screen display options. Login cookies are valid for 2 days and screen display cookies for 1 year. If you select “Remember me”, your login will be saved for 2 weeks. Once you log out of your account, login cookies will be deleted.

When you change or publish a message, an additional cookie is stored by your browser. This cookie contains no personal data and only has the post ID of the article you have edited. This cookie expires after one day.

Included Content from Other Websites
------------------------------------

Messages on this site may contain embedded content (e.g. youtube video’s). Embedded content from other websites behaves exactly the same as if the visitor has visited this other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, track third parties and monitor your interaction with embedded content, including your interaction with embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

How Long We Store Your Data
---------------------------

Your email address will be saved via MailChimp until you unsubscribe or indicate that you wish to delete your data.

You can read more about the data we collect for security and statistics purposes in the relevant sections.

What Rights Do You Have Over Your Data
--------------------------------------

If you have an account on this site you may request an export file of your personal information that we have from you, including any information you have provided to us.

You may also request that we delete any personal information we have about you. This does not include any information we are required to keep for administrative, legal or security purposes.

**A little bit more about buddho.org**  
Our mission is to enable people to live a moral, mindful and meaningful life, in the spirit of Theravāda Buddhism. The foundation believes that samatha meditation (concentration meditation) on buddho can offer a valuable contribution towards this goal.

**Questions or comments?**  

**Want to know more about our foundation?**  

**Looking for practical information?**  

**Support us**  

**Read the fine print**  

**Top 10 posts*** [What is Meditation?](https://buddho.org/meditation-for-beginners/)

**Switch language**

**Copyright © 2024 buddho.org**  
This work is licensed under [CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/?ref=chooser-v1)

**Enjoy your day!**
